HARRIET THOMPSON

A web developer with an analytical background in fashion buying and merchandising. I am excited to bring my experience of creative problem solving, analysis and team management into my new career in Web Development. I really enjoy working in a diverse team and pride myself on being a fast learner with a flexible attitude.

In addition to coding, I enjoy playing the drums and the violin, and spending as much time outdoors as possible, either hiking, skiing or camping.

Telephone: 236-999-6256 harrietrsthompson@gmail.com LinkedIn: harriet-thompson-

32925663/

github: github/hazthompson

PROJECTS

Jungle June 2019

Jungle was an independent project working on a full stack e-commerce application built with Rails.

This project encompassing fixing bugs and implementing new features. These features included user Authentication and admin security, email receipts and product ratings and comments.

PINIT! May 2019

Pinit! is a full stack web application built with Node, Express, jQuery, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS and SASS. This app stores and displays learning resources as images and URLs. These saved resources can be categorised, viewed individually, saved, ranked, liked and commented on.

In this collaborative project I created the back-end logic for the homepage, which included creating and searching resources. I also built the majority of the front-end views and styling for the app.

Tweeter May 2019

Tweeter is a simple AJAX-based, single-page Twitter clone using jQuery, HTML and CSS.

SKILL STACK

Languages & Frameworks

- Javascript
- Ruby on rails
- React
- HTML/CSS/SASS
- Node.js
- jQuery
- Bootstrap

Systems & Databases

- Git/GutHub
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL

EXPERIENCE

Oak + Fort

Production Manager, April 2017- April 2019

As Production Lead I developed strong leadership skills by managing and training three members of the team. I Oversaw the production process while collaborating closely across design, sourcing, and logistics teams. Using creative problem solving, I managed our supplier network to ensure good quality products met production timelines and margin target goals. I reported on these targets along with sales analysis and industry insights. These reports were used to influence future buys for the coming seasons.

Topshop - Arcadia Group

Merchandising Assistant, May 2014-Sept 2016

During my time in the Merchandising team I honed my analytical skills evaluating trends in sales data to influence decisions on future buys. Assisting in planning and forecasting trade, provided me with the confidence to flag risks and opportunities independently and to manage stocks accordingly. I developed strong presentation skills in weekly company meetings relaying lessons learnt to streamline future buying decisions. I developed strong leadership and communication skills by managing and training three members of the team.

Eighty Sixth Floor Music

Digital Marketing and Social Media Manager, Sept 2012- May 2014

As Digital Marketing and Social Media Manager I gained confident research and communication skills writing content for the website and social media platforms. I developed a strong understanding of SEO using Google Analytics and Adwords to analyze audience needs and predict trends.

EDUCATION

Web Development Bootcamp

Lighthouse Labs

A full-time web development bootcamp, covering topics such as javascript, Node.js, React, Ruby, HTML/CSS, MongoDB and PostgreSQL. This programme emulates a developers' work environment through a variation of individual exercises, pair programming and group projects.

University of Durham

Combined Honours in History & English Literature 2:1